Ahmad A. Abu Shanab

• Sunrise, FL 33351 • (765) 544 0606 • AASHANAB@HOTMAIL.COM

OBJECTIVE

A computer engineer professional having extensive experience in research, teaching, and information systems management, with proven effectiveness in presentation and communication, a leader and a project manager; driving organizational change through the analysis, acquisition, and integration of new technologies.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Computer Engineering, Florida Atlantic University, GPA 4.0/4.0

Boca Raton, Florida. Graduation date: May 2015

Dissertation: Analysis of Machine Learning Algorithms on Bioinformatics Data of Varying Quality

AREAS OF SPECIALIZATION

- Machine learning, Data mining, and Bioinformatics
- Programming using assembly language, C, C++, higher level languages
- Relational Database Management Systems and SQL
- Computer Networks and Security
- Management Information Systems (MIS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Florida Atlantic University

Research Assistant / Teaching Assistant / Instructor

Jan 2010 - Present

- Designed empirical studies (datasets, rankers, classifiers, sampling techniques, etc.).
- Migrated results to relational database management system (MS Access, Sybase, MS SQL).
- Aggregated results in tables and figures using SQL, MS Excel, Power Builder.
- Performed statistical analysis on results (ANOVA).
- Taught the following classes:
 - Introduction to logic design (Spring 2010, Summer 2010, Fall 2010, Spring 2011)
 - Introduction to microprocessor systems (Fall 2011, Spring 2012, Fall 2013)
- Prepared course syllabi including in class and outside of class assignments and graded students work and provided appropriate and timely feedback to all students.
- Designed lab experiments and exams to simulate real-life implementations.
- Served as a book reviewer for my department by evaluating and approving courses textbooks.

Jordan River Foundation

Manager of Information Systems Technology

May 2005 – Dec 2008

- Formulated, applied, and reviewed information systems policies and procedures, which defined the roles of the information systems department and IT employees.
- Prepared the information systems department action plan to help accomplish the organization's mission and drive toward the vision.
- Assessed and acquired new technologies (ERP, CRM, KMS, etc.) to support strategic and operational activities.
- Analyzed information systems monthly expenses for budget preparation and evaluation.
- Planned and acquired disaster recovery technologies to ensure business continuity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Continued)

Jordan River Foundation

Information Technology Officer

Dec 2003 – May 2005

- Administered IT infrastructure (Windows Servers, Network, Applications, Databases, etc.) to ensure seamless service.
- Planned, enforced, and audited software and hardware security measures resulting in a secure work environment.
- Developed software modules to meet different departments software needs, which helped increase productivity of all departments and reduced errors.
- Performed hardware and software troubleshooting procedures, providing superior technical support service.

Tantash Information Systems Group

Software Developer

April 2002 – Dec 2003

- Assessed customer's software requirements and converted software requirements to formal language to ensure the delivery of the desired software functionalities.
- Performed software analysis and design to guide development efforts.
- Tested and debugged software (unit testing, system testing, integration testing), to improve the quality of software modules released and ensure bug-free software releases.
- Built generic and custom statistical and graphical reports, which helped customers in making decisions and assisted in strategies formulation.
- Performed help desk activities (on site, remotely, over the phone), to provide the best customer service and ensure customer satisfaction.
- Administered databases (creation, fine tuning, back up, migration) to guarantee high speed data storage and retrieval, and ensure continuous data availability.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

1.	Tau Beta Pi	May 2011 - Present
2.	Upsilon Pi Epsilon	May 2011 - Present
3.	Phi Kappa Phi	Mar 2010 - Present
4.	Golden Key	Oct 2009 - Present

REFERENCES

- Taghi Khoshgoftaar, Professor. Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Road Boca Raton, FL 33431, (561) 297-3994, khoshgof@fau.edu.
- Mohammad Ilyas, Dean and Professor. Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Road Boca Raton, FL 33431, (561) 297-3454, ilyas@fau.edu.
- Bassem Alhalabi, Associate Professor. Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Road Boca Raton, FL 33431, (561) 297-3182, alhalabi@fau.edu.
- Imad Mahgoub, Professor, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Road Boca Raton, FL 33431, (561) 297-3458, mahgoubi@fau.edu.